A Guide to the Benjamin Cottrell Papers, 1910-1983
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Benjamin Cottrell Papers, 1910-1983
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1994-035
1.7 cu. ft. 7 boxes; 2 folders
This collection contains the papers, photographs, diplomas, certificates, correspondence, and scrapbooks of Benjamin Cottrell from 1910-1983. Cottrell, a 1916 VPI graduate with a degree in Civil Engineering, spent part of his career working on railroads and highways in Central and South America.
Cottrell, Benjamin
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
This collection was acquired by Special Collections in 1972.
Biographical Note
Benjamin Cottrell graduated from Virginia Polytechnic Institute in 1916 with a bachelors in Civil Engineering. He spent most of his life working in railroad and highway development in South America. He was a member of the VPI Alumni Century Club. Cottrell died in 1972.
Scope and Content
This collection contains the papers, photographs, diplomas, certificates, correspondence, and scrapbooks of Benjamin Cottrell. Cottrell graduated from VPI in 1916 and spent his career working as a highway and railroad engineer in Costa Rica and Bolivia. Much of the newspapers, scrapbooks, photographs, and other papers in the collection relate to his work abroad. Other materials relate to his activities as a VPI alumnus.
Arrangement
The collection is organized by material type.
Subjects:
University Archives; Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute
Contents List
- Papers, 1910-1972
  - Address Books (Box-folder 1-1)
  - Blank Postcards (Box-folder 1-2)
  - Certificates and Awards (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Watercolor Print of South American Church (Box-folder 1-5)
- Awards and Plaques, 1951-1983, n.d.
  - Century Club Member Brass Plaques 1975-1983 (Box 2)
  - VPI Alumni Century Club Framed Award of Appreciation, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Carved Wooden Name Plaque (Box 7)
  - Commemorative Medal (Box 7)
  - Awards, 1951-1954 (Folder 2)
- Artifacts, 1960, n.d.
  - American Legion Philippines Cap (Box 7)
  - Fez Freemason Cap (Box 7)
  - "Last Spike Ceremony" Commemorative Railroad Peg, December 1960 (Box 7)
- Photographs, 1916-1968
  - Photographs (Box 4)
- Scrapbooks, n.d.
  - Scrapbook (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook of Brazil (1 of 2) (Box 6)
  - Scrapbook of Brazil (2 of 2) (Box 6)
- Newspapers and Magazines, 1954
  - Life Magazine (Spanish edition) Noveber 1954 (Folder 1)
  - Life Magazine November 1954 (Folder 1)
  - El Dario Newspaper (Folder 2)
    - September 26th, 1954
    - September 28th, 1954
    - September 29th, 1954
    - September 30th, 1954